The world is in a chaos right now and
the markets are crashing. In this video,
I'm going to show you strategies which
can be very profitable in volatile
market conditions like this when most
traders are losing money. I'm going to
show you two strategies, one for large
accounts and one for small accounts.
I've made more than 100k in realized
profit this month and I'm going to show
you my strategies behind the scenes
including my real trade breakdowns. If
you stay till the end, I'm also going to
show you a trade which went into a loss
and how I made a simple adjustment to
turn it around and turn it into a
massive profit. This video is for
education only. Any examples shared in
this video are for demonstration
purposes. They are not recommendations.
I'm not a financial advisor. So, talk to
your financial advisor and do your own
research before making any decision.
Options trading is highly risky and past
performance is not an indication of
future results. Before we go into the
strategies, let me show you my actual
results. This is E-Trade which is one of
the top US-based regulated broker and
this is one of my account. You can see
here today there is $0 profit in it
because I did not make any trades today.
And if we change the dates from March
1st to March 20th, so we can see
month-to-date 20 days performance. I've
made about $13,392
in this account month-to-date and you
see something here called deferred loss.
This is not an actual loss. What this
means is in an options there are two
sides. One side is going to make profit,
one side is going to lose. So, the IRS
do not want you to be able to write off
tax loss from the losing side which is
why it shows up here as deferred loss
because I am not allowed to write it off
for tax purposes. But after that, the
net profit is $13,392.
I have also verified this account on a
third-party platform called Kinfo and
you can see details for that in the
description below. And this is my second
account where I have a realized gain of
$1,639
today. But you can see here that today I
also have a $14,900
of unrealized loss because this account
is a mix of a long-term and my active
trading. And obviously the market and
obviously the Nasdaq was down more than
2% today. So, this account is down more
than 2% as well. But you also see that I
also have 336,000 of unrealized gain in
this account and the net account value
is close to a million dollars. So now,
let's change the dates here from March
1st to 20th and you can see here my
total realized gain for this month is
$99,800.
So, both of these accounts combined
approximately $114,000
in realized gains. Let's discuss the
state of the market right now. S&P is in
a clear downtrend. We have broke the
200-day moving average and S&P is now at
6,500 down from 7,000. But looking into
context it feels like it is down a lot
but we are actually only down about 7%
from the all-time highs. We are not even
in a 10% correction territory yet. Back
in 2022 when the market was going down
and I kept buying the dip and it was
very brutal. The market kept going down
all year long and there was no end in
sight. Every day it felt like getting
punched in the face. In the long term,
it worked out okay because I made a lot
of long-term investments but in the
short term, it was very painful and I
learned a very expensive lesson that
everyone is a genius in a bull market
and I can no longer rely on strategies
which only work in a bull market. And
that's when I started to go deep into
delta neutral strategies because in
delta neutral strategies, market
direction does not make much difference
because we profit from theta decay. The
market can go up, down, or in circles
and we can still find opportunities to
make profit even in a down year. So,
what is delta neutral? Now, most traders
think that you need the market to go up
to make money. You buy stock or call
options. If you're right, you make
profit. If you're wrong, you lose money.
But in delta neutral, we look at the
market in a completely different way.
Instead [snorts] of looking at if the
market is going up or down, we look at a
range. It's a range-based strategy. So,
we like to trade in a predefined range
and as long as the market stays in this
range we make profit. You often hear
about day traders complaining about the
choppy markets, everyone losing money in
a choppy markets. Most of the time,
market is actually choppy. And that's
where delta neutral strategies can make
profit all the time. Delta neutral
strategies are evergreen but they can be
even more profitable in a volatile
conditions like this. There are several
types of delta neutral strategies for
different market conditions like
strangle, straddle, iron condor, iron
fly, butterfly, and calendar spreads. In
this videos, I'm going to teach you two
strategies but in my upcoming video, I'm
going to teach you even more
high-performing strategies. So, don't
forget to hit the like and subscribe
button so you can get my latest strategy
videos. Before we go into the
strategies, you also need to understand
this concept of volatility and how it
makes it even more profitable to trade
these strategies in market conditions
like this. VIX is called the fear index.
It is the index of market volatility and
typically it is trading around 15.
Anything under 15 is usually low. When
it gets over 15, things start to heat
up. Right now, we are trading between 25
to 30 which is pretty high. Most of the
times when market is in a fear, VIX goes
high and when market goes down, VIX also
comes down. When VIX is high, options
premium skyrocket and make options way
more expensive. Let's say you buy an
option in the market moves in your
direction you can still end up losing
the trade because of something called
the volatility crush. Because you are
buying inflated premium right now, when
VIX goes down, those option prices are
also going to come down which means that
even if you're right, you can still end
up losing money which makes it a perfect
opportunity to sell options instead
because right now I can sell options and
I can get paid way more. There are
options which I was selling for couple
hundred dollars a few weeks ago. Those
same options are now worth $500. So, I
can make much more money when volatility
is high. Now, let's put these concepts
into practice using a couple of
different strategies to see how it works
in our favor. The first strategy is
called the short strangle. Short
strangle is the basis of most of the
delta neutral strategies. It typically
has higher capital requirement. It's not
for everyone but even if you are not
going to trade this strategy, it's still
very important to understand this
strategy because this is the building
blocks of the strategies you are going
to learn in the next step. In a short
strangle, we are going to sell an
out-of-the-money call and put and
collect premium from both the sides.
Let's say a stock is trading at $100. I
can go out and sell a 95 strike put and
I can also sell a 105 strike call and I
collect premium from both the sides.
Now, it will create a payoff chart like
this where I make profit as long as the
stock stays in this range from 95 to
105. If the stock stays in this range I
get to pocket the premium I've collected
from both the sides and the options
expired worthless. The reason why it
works so well is because the theta decay
is working for us and if we were to sell
just a put, I would collect premium from
one side. But here since I'm also
selling a call, I'm collecting twice the
premium for the same capital
requirement. And volatility crush is
also going to work in my favor. If VIX
starts to come down, even if the prices
of the market is not moving much, I'm
going to profit from both the sides
because of the volatility crush. And in
this case, I do not need to be right on
the direction. I just need to pick a
range. In this example, I have picked 95
to 105 range. But if you want, you can
pick a much wider range. You can even go
with 90 to 110 dollar range. That will
give you a 10% up or down protection.
Now, let me show you a real trade
example where I made $2,500 just
yesterday. So yesterday, QQQ opened at
589 and after the market settled down
for about 30 minutes or 1 hour, I
usually go out and sell an
out-of-the-money strangle. So yesterday,
I sold 587 strike put and then I also
sold a 595 strike call. Now, after this,
throughout the day market went up and
down a little. It was very choppy and
for a while it also went up. So, when I
enter a trade like this I just need the
market to stay within this channel and
if the market stays in this channel, I
get to pocket the premium I collected
from both sides. So, in this case, I
collected about $2,700 in premium for
selling the strangle at 587 and 595
strike and I was able to close my trade
before 3:00 p.m. for 90% profit where I
was able to capture $2,560
for 20 lots. I make a trade like this
almost daily and it works very, very
well. But there is one catch with this.
Selling a strangle like this requires
about $9,000 in capital. Now, it might
look like I'm just collecting $140,150
for 9,000 but I'm collecting that daily.
So, if you add it over weeks and months,
it adds up to a lot of money. And the
other thing is there are ways to change
this trade into another strategy but we
can actually make a trade like this with
just a few hundred dollars and I'm going
to show you that in the next step. When
we are selling a strangle, we can sell
it for any trade duration. Let's say I
want to sell this triangle for QQQ
expiring in about 4 weeks. So, I can
select a date like this.
Then the next thing we need to do is
select strikes.
I typically like to start at 20 delta
and then calibrate to find my best
setup. So, let's say in this case we can
sell a put at 550 and we can sell a call
at 610 strike. This will give us 24
delta on the call side and approximately
23 delta on the put side. So, slightly
more than 20, but it works for this
example. Now, it will create this kind
of payoff diagram where I have a very
wide range where I can make profit. If
the price goes out of this range, then I
can start to lose. And this range is
pretty wide. My break-even point is 538
on the downside, 621 to the upside
because the premium we receive for
selling this option is going to offset
our break-even point as well. So, I have
about 6.5% to the upside and 7% to the
downside. As long as stock trades in
this range,
I get to keep this credit. And the
credit I will receive for this trade is
about $1,184
for about $9,000 in margin. So, on
$9,000
I can make about 13% return if the stock
trades in this range, even if the market
goes up, down, or in circles. As long as
the stock stays in this range, I get to
pocket this premium. But I typically
never sell overnight strangles. The
reason for that is if there is a black
swan event overnight where the market
gaps up or down by more than 5%, I can
be in a significant loss. So, I'm more
comfortable selling strangles intraday
where I can use a stop loss to protect
my downside because I don't want to lose
more money than the reward. So, if I'm
collecting $100, my stop loss is also
going to be $100 for an even risk-reward
scenario. And in that case, I only need
slightly more than 50% to be profitable.
And in that case, as long as I win more
than 50% of my trade, I can be
profitable. Now, strangles is not for
everyone, especially not for newbies.
So, I'm going to teach you another
strategy which we can do with just a few
hundred dollars and which is much lower
risk. That strategy is called the iron
condor. The way iron condor works is we
start with a strangle. So, let's say a
stock is trading at $100. We sell a 95
put, we sell a 105 call, and then we can
go out of the money and buy hedges for
protection. So, in this case,
after selling the 95 put, I'm going to
buy a 90 put,
and then I will sell a 105 call and buy
110 call for protection. What this is
going to do is it will turn our trade
into a defined risk setup. It requires
much less capital. It is lower risk, but
it has very similar mechanics as the
strangle. So, let's go into the options
trade and convert the strangle trade
into an iron condor. So, after selling
550 put, I can go out and buy a put
which is about 10 points out of the
money. So, selling 550 put and buying
540 put. And same thing I can do on the
call side as well. So, I can sell 610
call and buy a 620 call. Now, this will
reduce our credit from more than $1,000
to 413,
but in this case, our capital
requirement is only 587,
and that is also our max loss. So, in a
worst-case scenario, if the market moves
more than 5%, the maximum I can lose is
$587.
So, if I'm risking $587
to make $413 upside, that is a very good
payoff. So, in this kind of trade, I can
make about 70% return on my capital in
just 4 weeks. But there is something
even better which is working in our
favor. Like I said, when VIX is high,
the premiums go up. So, in this case,
typically if I were to make a trade like
this, maybe I will only get $200 credit.
But now in this case, for such a wide
range, I'm getting $400 credit. So, when
VIX starts to come down, let's say
implied volatility comes down. So, out
of the 70% profit I want to make, I can
actually make most of that profit in
just a couple of weeks if the stock
stays in this range and VIX comes down.
When VIX goes high, typically after that
the next logical step is that it cools
down. But in this case, even if it does
not cool down, even if it stays in this
range, I'm collecting such high theta
premium that I can make profit as long
as it stays in this range. And this is
getting me a very wide break-even range
of
$545 to $614.
So, that means I can make profit even if
the stock goes up by 5% or even if it
goes down by 6%. I can make profit in
both directions.
And another benefit of high VIX is that
it is going to get us much wider range.
Typically, if I were to sell a 20 or 25
delta iron condor like this,
I would only get 2 to 3% range on both
sides. But here we are getting well over
5% range on both sides. So, which is why
these kind of strategies can be even
more profit during volatile market
conditions like this compared to the
regular calmer markets. Now, let me show
you an actual trade where I opened a
trade couple of weeks ago. My range
breached. It went into a loss, but still
I was able to make a simple adjustment
and turn it into a $5,000 profit trade.
So, let me show you a real trade
breakdown which I also shared in my
private Discord community. SPX was
trading at 6850 at that time. So, I
opened an iron condor in about 8 days
expiration where I selected 6700 put on
the downside and 7000 call on the
upside. That means I will make profit if
SPX trades between 6700 to 7000. I
collected about $910 premium for each
contract. That means my risk would be
about $1,600 for an upside of $900 in
about 8 days. The trade first went into
a profit of 16% in the first day, but
after a couple of days, the trade went
into a loss because SPX broke down under
6700. So, at that point my trade was in
about 10 to 20% loss, but instead of
panicking, I did a simple adjustment
which turned this trade around into a
massive profit. So, all I had to do was
I closed the existing strikes of 6700
and 7000, and I chose new strike with
6400 put and 6900 call, which gave me a
very wide, much wider range than before.
And also, I extended my expiration date
by another week. So, in this case, my
total cost of this roll was about 1.5
debit. So, at this point, initially I
received about $910 credit, and now I
paid back $150 out of it. So, at this
point, I still have more than $750 to
work with, and that can be my profit.
Then what happened after that? In just a
couple of days, the trade actually
turned back into green, and in another
week or so, it actually captured most of
the profit, and it was at 67% profit in
just 1 week. And then after a few more
days, it was at 90% profit. And this is
the current state of that trade. It
expired today on March 20th, and it
expired with 100% profit even though S&P
dropped even more at 6500.
Remember, when I opened this trade, SPX
was 6850, and it dropped 350%.
And still this trade ended up making
100% profit. So, after the cost of
rolling and everything, I made well over
$5,000 profit in this trade. So, you see
that with strategies like this,
we can work our way out of a trade even
if it completely turns against us. And
it's not just me, people in my program
are also crushing it. You can see that
this person made $9,290
using strategies like this. This person
made
$2,995
in a day,
$7,500 in a day,
$28,000
in a month,
another 2,500 in a day, $1,500 in a day,
2,500 in a day, $5,000 gain in a day
trading similar strategies like this. If
you want to learn my next level
strategies where we can make profit in
any market condition, regardless if the
market is going up, down, or in circles,
there are different strategies for
different market conditions, including
the adjustment and rolling strategies,
how to manage your trade and turn it
into a profit or break-even when things
go against you, check out my coaching
program in the description below. In
this program, I share my next level
strategies which I cannot share on
YouTube. And it's not just a basic level
simple program. In this program, you can
get started as a beginner, but you can
learn everything I learned in the 5
years in just a few months and become a
very proficient trader. Or if you just
want to join my private Discord
community, you can also check it out in
the description below. To manage this
trade, I like to follow this 50% rule.
It has two components to it. The first
is when a trade like this goes to 50%
profit, that is usually the optimal time
to take profit because when we take
profit at 50%
and roll that capital into the next
trade, that is where we can generate the
highest annualized return.
And the other component is that if I
open a trade for 4 weeks duration at 2
weeks mark, I'm looking to get out of
the trade either for a profit or a small
loss or break even or if it needs an
adjustment, I would make an adjustment
by the 2 week mark because after 2 week
the risk in the trade is going to
significantly increase because of gamma
risk. So, what I would like to do is if
my trade horizon is 2 weeks, I'm going
to open a trade with 4 week duration.
So, if my trade outlook is 1 week, I'm
going to open a trade with 2 week
duration with a plan to get out of the
trade in the midway. When we follow
these rules, we can get a higher win
rate with smaller losses and better risk
management. Tasty Trade has also done a
lot of research on this and they say
that this is the way to go. Just like
any other strategy, this also has
certain risk. There is no free lunch in
this world. You need to have a defined
loss before entry. So, if I'm selling a
strangle, I would typically use a stop
loss for it, but if I'm selling an iron
condor, I don't use a stop loss on iron
condor because it is defined risk. The
way to do that is position sizing. So,
if I'm making an iron condor trade, I am
not going to risk more than 2 to 4% of
my capital. My stop loss is not based on
it going down certain percentage. First,
I would try to make an adjustment and
see if I can get out at a break even. If
things are completely going against me
and the market trend has changed, then I
would be okay to exit at a small loss.
But when you enter a trade like this,
you have to be prepared for the max loss
scenario. So, you only take position
which you are okay in case if it goes to
zero. With any strategy, just start with
one contract as at first and or even
start with paper trading until you get
fluent with it. And you need to have an
adjustment plan before you enter this
trade.
A lot of people message me on the day of
expiration when the trade has gone down
90% and they ask me how do I adjust it
now.
That is not the time to adjust. If you
plan on making an adjustment, you need
to know about it before you enter the
trade and you should make the adjustment
before the halfway mark.
And take profits when you see it. Don't
try to squeeze out the every last
dollar. The ideal profit target is about
50% and sometimes I can hold also more
than 50%, but this kind of setup has
diminishing returns.
Let's say if I sell an iron condor with
$1,000 credit, the maximum I can make in
that trade is $1,000. So, once it goes
to
$500 profit, at that point,
I'm risking $2,000 to make the next
$500.
When it goes to $800 profit, at that
point, I'm risking $2,300
to make the last $200. So, at that
point, the juice is not worth the risk.
If you like this video, don't forget to
hit the like and subscribe button and
check out other videos on my channel
where you can learn more strategies like
this.